Guide to the Colin Davis Waterfront Workers Oral History Collection OH.060
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Colin Davis Waterfront Workers Oral History Collection
1995-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Davis, Colin J (Colin John), 1954-
OH.060
1 Linear Feet in 1 compact disk box and two card catalog drawers.
These seventeen interviews of longshoremen document their experiences working on waterfronts in New York, New Jersey, and London during the middle of the twentieth century. Subjects discussed include entry into the occupation, working conditions, characteristics of different cargoes, labor relations, relationship between rank and file union members and leadership, ethnic composition on the docks, and Communist Party activity on waterfront. The interviews were taken by Colin J. Davis and used in his 2003 book Waterfront Revolts: New York and London Dockworkers, 1946-1961.
Conditions Governing Access
Materails are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Colin J. Davis in 2007. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.049.
Arrangement
Master cassettes are arranged by assigned cassette numbers. Access compact disks are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the interviewee.
Historical/Biographical Note
Professor Colin J. Davis of the School of Social Science and Behavioral Sciences at the University of Alabama at Birmingham took these interviews as part of a study of the New York City waterfront. Interviews were used in Davis' 2003 book Waterfront Revolts: New York and London Dockworkers, 1946-1961.
Scope and Contents
The collection is contains seventeen interviews with longshoremen regarding their experiences working on the waterfront during the middle of the twentieth century. Subjects discussed include entry into the occupation, working conditions, characteristics of different cargoes, labor relations, relationship between rank and file union members and leadership, ethnic composition on docks, and Communist Party activity on waterfront. Interviewees worked in Manhattan, Brooklyn, and New Jersey. Additionally, there are four interviews with workers from the London, England docks: Pye, Donovan, Bloomberg, and Johns.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Stevedores |x Labor Unions; Stevedores -- New York (State) -- New York -- Interviews.; Working class -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Frank Barbaro, Jul 6, 1995 (Box 1, Cd Barbaro 1, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 1)
- Pete Bell, Jul 07, 1995 (Box 1, Cd Bell 1, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 1)
- Joe Bloomberg, Aug 5, 1996 (Box 1, Cd Bloomberg 1-2, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 2)
- Joe Bloomberg, Aug 7, 1996 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 12, Box 1, Cd Bloomberg 3)
- Leonard DiFazio, Jul 12, 1995 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 3, Box 1, Cd L. DiFazio 1)
- Sebastien DiFazio, Jul 10, 1995 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 4, Box 1, Cd S. DiFazio 1)
- John Donovan, Aug 9, 1996 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 5, Box 1, Cd Donovan 1)
- "Eddie", 1995 (Box 1, Cd Eddie 1, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 6)
- Ted Johns, Jul 11, 1996 (Box 1, Cd Johns 1-2, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 7)
- Morris Klopot, Jul 13, 1995 (Box 1, Cd Klopot 1-2, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 9, Cassette 3)
- Vincent Longhi, Sep 29, 1995 (Box 1, Cd Longhi 1, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 8)
- Harold Mailman, Jun 12, 1998 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 10, Box 1, Cd Mailman 1)
- Angelo Pacifico, Jul 12, 1995 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 4, Box 1, Cd Pacifico 1)
- George Pye, Aug 14, 1996 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 11, Box 1, Cd Pye 1-2)
- Philip Sipser, Jun 29, 1995 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 6, Box 1, Cd Sipser 1)
- Larry Sullivan, Jul 13, 1995 (Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 9, Box 1, Cd Sullivan 1)
- Audrey West, Jun 22, 1995 (Box 1, Cd West 1, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 14)
- Jose Villa, Dec 16, 1996 (Box 1, Cd Villa 1, Box Shared Cassette Box 14, Cassette 13)